

6036 Warbling Ln., Westerville, OH 43081
(614) 561-2440
<a href="mailto:thekimlandis@yahoo.com">thekimlandis@yahoo.com</a>
https://www.linkedin.com/in/kimlandis

As an experienced technical writer, I offer a diverse skill set that includes documentation, editing, user experience, code sample authoring, and Japanese translation. I have spent the past four plus years managing and marking up GitHub content for Microsoft Learn training in the C + E Skilling department and tracking it in Azure DevOps. Here is a link to my portfolio in GitHub.

#### **Skills**

- GitHub operations and Acrolinx
- Azure DevOps and SharePoint
- Online training format compliance
- Visual Studio Code (md, yml files)
- Grammar, spelling, punctuation, editing
- GitHub, Jira, TFS, Mercurial, StarTeam
- UX and UAT

- Red Tiger video source control
- HelpStudio, RoboHelp, Snaglt, Confluence
- HTML, HTML5, and wiki markup
- GitHub-flavored markdown (GFM)
- Agile, scrum team, sprints
- End-user help, flow charts, tutorials, user guides, and API documentation (C#, VB)

# **Experience**

JULY 1, 2022 - AUGUST 30, 2024

### Platform Operations Eng. Lead / Microsoft (Centific), Remote

- From Word content, create GitHub folder structures and markdown content and media
- In Visual Studio Code, GitHub Desktop, and GitHub online, guide content through Microsoft requirements including meeting Acrolinx scores and other guidelines
- Track work items for training modules, learning paths, module updates, and customer feedback
- Manage video content in Red Tiger
- Triage or fix customer-reported content bugs

JUNE 1, 2020 – JULY 1, 2022

## Content Manager / Microsoft (Disys), Remote

- From Word content, created GitHub folder structures and markdown content and media
- In Visual Studio Code, GitHub Desktop, and GitHub online, guided content through Microsoft requirements including meeting Acrolinx scores and other guidelines
- Tracked work items for training modules, learning paths, updates, and customer feedback
- Triaged or fixed customer-reported content bugs

#### Technical Writer / Stratifyd, Charlotte, North Carolina

- Created documentation from scratch in a Confluence Knowledge Base
- Wrote 227 knowledge base articles on AI analyses and data connectors in under 10 months
- Performed user acceptance testing (UAT) and reported and tracked issues in Jira
- Documented internal processes for on-site AWS setup

JANUARY 4, 2018 - FEBRUARY 22, 2019

#### Technical Writer / EmpowerID, Dublin, Ohio

- Reformatted hundreds of topics from a proprietary documentation tool into Confluence
- Documented dozens of new features in EmpowerID identity access management software
- Provided code Samples in C#, Powershell, and SQL

FEBRUARY 16, 2010 - NOVEMBER 30, 2017

#### Senior Tech Writer / GrapeCity, Raleigh

- Documented ActiveReports Server for end users and administrators
- Documented ActiveReports for developers with code snippets for the API (C#, Visual Basic.NET)
- Documented Wijmo for JavaScript developers with code samples for the API (JavaScript)
- As Assoc. Product Manager (4/2015-3/2017), represented products at trade shows and published case studies
- As Content Marketing Manager (4/2017-11/2018), created and updated web content (markdown), marketing content, blog posts, emails, forum announcements, and ad copy

AUGUST, 2008 - DECEMBER, 2008

#### Tech Writer / Honda of America, Mfg., Marysville, Ohio

- Created courseware (RoboHelp) for engineers learning new Teamcenter PLM software
- Wrote internal documentation for SharePoint users

MAY, 2007 - AUGUST, 2008

### Tech Writer / vSync, Columbus, Ohio

- Created a quick start guide for vShip end users
- Updated fifteen years' worth of outdated internal documents
- Documented six Microsoft Dynamics products from scratch (HelpStudio)
- Provided a single source of documentation for internal and end-user-facing help files
- Made extensive User Experience suggestions for the UI that enabled the product to receive Microsoft Dynamics Partner certification

#### **Education**

### B.A. Japanese / The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio

Kim Landis | 6036 Warbling Ln., Westerville, OH 43081 | (614) 561-2440 | thekimlandis@yahoo.com

#### Microsoft Certified Professional / Columbus, Ohio

# **Volunteering Activities**

**2023 - PRESENT** 

### **Mentoring/** Self

Mentoring and empowering young women of low socioeconomic means

2013 - 2022

# Pantry Assistant/ Mid-Ohio Foodbank

**Poverty Alleviation** 

2008 - 2018

# Voter Registration/ HeadCount.org

Nonpartisan Civil Rights and Social Action